High Lea, Chatsworth Avenue
Haslemere, United Kingdom, GU27 1BA
+447595302997
ruperthorlick@gmail.com
www.github.com/ruhatch

RUPERT HORLICK

I am a Computer Scientist, Software Engineer, and Environmental Educator with experience in functional programming and its mathematical foundations. I also have experience facilitating teams and coaching them to adopt self-organising practices.

ind Coacining	them to adopt sen-organising practices.
	Experience
Jan 2024 – Present	Chief Techonology Officer, Money&Co. Took ownership of entire tech stack for FinTech platform. Migrated to kubernetes on AWS, deploying through GitHub actions. This reduced downtime, streamlined the development process, and made the whole system generally more reliable.
Jan 2022 – Present	Director and Facilitator , <i>Climate Clarity CIC</i> . Founded and grew climate education start-up from nothing to £200k revenue. Handled all aspects of business, from incorporation to finance. Designed and built website, and evovled other tech systems to support the businesses needs.
Dec 2020 – Jun 2021	Haskell Developer, Stack Builders. Three-month project to exposing API for existing software solution. Delivered on time and on budget.
Jun 2020 – Dec 2020	Senior Engineer, Regen Network Development. Spearheaded improvements in testing across the core Regen Ledger by adding property tests. Worked closely with CTO to design and implement an ecocredit trading platform.
May 2018 - Sep 2019	Senior Haskell Developer, <i>IOHK</i> . Formalised, implemented, and property tested ledger rules for Cardano blockchain. Personally designed and prototyped a hard-fork combinator to allow seamless transition across major protocol updates.
Sep 2017 – May 2018	Lead Software Developer, Money&Co. Prototyped legacy Java codebase using Haskell and Nix.
Mar 2017 - Sep 2017	Software Development Engineer , <i>Myrtle Software</i> . Worked on compiling neural networks to FPGAs, using Haskell and Nix. Was offered a senior position, including responsibility for team productivity.
	Skills

Education

• Haskell, Rust, OCaml, Go

o Javascript, Nix, Python, Java

Programming

Languages

2016 - 2017	MEng Computer Science , <i>University of Cambridge</i> , Distinction. <i>Thesis:</i> Formalised the theory of Generalised Species in Homotopy Type Theory (HoTT) using Agda. Was offered research position to continue the work.
2013 - 2016	BA Computer Science , <i>University of Cambridge</i> , 1st Class (81%, Rank: 8/81). Implemented Path ORAM, a cryptographic primitive, in OCaml to search encrypted documents. Analysed performance and security properties in a dissertation.

Tools

o kubernetes, git, AWS

o GitHub Actions, LTFX